# Aleksander Fret

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/aleksander-fret GitHub: www.github.com/alemikolo portfolio: www.aleksander.fret.com.pl

e-mail: aleksander.fret@op.pl

tel.: 605 768 401



# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Front-End Developer Creating applications and web sites using modern front-end

technologies, like JS ES6, React, Redux, Webpack...,

ability to use some of the back-end technologies - PHP and

MySQL,

designing user interfaces (big experience in fhe field of

graphics, interest in UI UX).

Graphic Designer and Cartographer

Extensive editorial practice – designing of publications, DTP,

broad qualifications in the field of graphics software,

Big experience in making various maps.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Personal project Under construction: developing my online CV (React), which is

intended to replace my current portfolio site.

Udacity 11.2017–08.2018 (student): www.pixel-art-maker.fret.com.pl,

www.memorygame.fret.com.pl, www.arcadegame.fret.com.pl,

www.amusementparks.fret.com.pl.

Eko-Graf 10.2008–now: Cartographer – Map Editor. Duties: designing

of graphic layouts and covers, editorial and cartographic tasks, DTP, creating of advertising materials, preparing for printing.

WilMat 10.2016: www.wilmat.com.pl.

Emilia Fret 07.2015: www.psychoterapia.fret.com.pl.

Ewa Fret 01.2015: www.ewa.fret.com.pl.

Via Mercatorum 11.2012: www.warsztatyprzyrodnicze.com, logo, press

advertisement, advertising leaflet.

Others 04.2007–07.2008: SeaStar, Cartographer,

11.2005–12.2006: Nowa Era, Author: *Statistical tables*, 09.2004–03.2005: Wydawnictwo Marek Rożak, Cartographer.

## EDUCATION

Udacity 11.2017–08.2018: Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

**Program** (scholarship from Google)

Certain courses and trainings

React 16 – the complete guide (now); The Complete Sass & SCSS Course; PHP – developing CMS; PHP, MySQL, JS.

University of Wroclaw

10.1999–07.2005: bachelor's degree in *Geography*, master's degree in *Geography*, specialization in *Cartography*.

# QUALIFICATIONS

#### **Programming**

JS ES6, OOP, React, Redux, JQuery, SASS, CSS, HTML, RWD, accessibility, SEO, PHP, MySQL, Twig, Webpack, Gulp, Git.

#### Graphics software

CorelDRAW, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Photo-Paint.

#### Others

English language (b1), Global Mapper.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Award in the competition organized by Ministry of Transport and Construction for master thesis *Atlas regional*ny województwa łódzkiego.

III prize for "[...] modern editorial style, usability [...]", Wrocław – przewodnik (J. Czerwiński, Eko-Graf), XX Ogólnopolski Przegląd Książki Krajoznawczo-Turystycznej. Scope of work: graphic design and creation, DTP.

## PERSONAL TRAITS

Creative, with attention to detail, reliable, responsible, strongly involved.

#### INTERESTS

Playing the guitar, listening to the music, board games, fantasy literature, games and films, football, mountain hiking, listening to the Trojka radio channel.

I hereby give consent for my personal data to be processed for the purposes of recruitment, in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act dated 29.08.1997 (uniform text: Journal of Laws of the Republic of Poland 2002 No 101, item 926 with further amendments).